{"data":{"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","address":"12729 W Seven Mile Rd","zipcode":"48235","owner":"Mark Dabish","licenseNumber":"230555","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","mostRecentLicenseDate":"5/7/2018","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","geom":"0101000020E61000005CBD66C6F6CA54C0D0431D8B2A374540","inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"44419","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","inspectionDate":"2018-12-11T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"139","pcount":"0","pfcount":"1","ccount":"4","criticalcount":"1","noncritical":"4","correctedcritical":"1","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"44419","inspectionDate":"12/11/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"6-202.11","violationDescription":"Except as otherwise approved, light bulbs shall be shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistant in areas where there is exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Light shielding","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"inspectionid":"44419","inspectionDate":"12/11/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"6-501.11","violationDescription":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Physical facilities","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"Ceiling (s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Repair"},{"inspectionid":"44419","inspectionDate":"12/11/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\r\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\r\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\r\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN FREEZER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"inspectionid":"44419","inspectionDate":"12/11/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-603.11","violationDescription":"If an animal FOOD such as  beef, EGGS, FISH, lamb, milk, pork, POULTRY, or shellfish is served or sold raw, undercooked, or without otherwise being processed to eliminate pathogens, either in a READY-TO-EAT form or as an ingredient in another READY-TO-EAT FOOD, the PERMIT HOLDER shall inform CONSUMERS of the significantly increased RISK of consuming such FOODS, by using menu advisories, brochures, lable statements, table tents, placards, or other effective written means. (Pf)\r\nFOOD LAW SEC 6149\r\n...The food establishment may provide the following statement on selection information so that it is made pulblicly available: \"Ask your server about menu items that are cooked to order or served raw.  Consuming raw or undercooked, meats, poultry, shellfish, or eggs may increase your risk of foodborne illness.\"\r\nThe statements must be in a minimum of 11 point font and in a color that provides a clear contrast to background.\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Menu advisories","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2019-01-07T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"inspectionid":"44419","inspectionDate":"12/11/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\r\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\r\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\r\n","violationType":"Core","criticalViolationType":"No","itemDescription":"Plumbing system","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not maintained","subProblem":"","location":"MOP SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Maintain in good repair"}]},{"inspectionid":"42383","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","inspectionDate":"2018-05-31T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"127","pcount":"4","pfcount":"1","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"5","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"4","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"42383","inspectionDate":"5/31/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"HOT HOLDING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"42383","inspectionDate":"5/31/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \r\n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\r\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\r\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\r\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\r\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\r\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\r\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"Raw ready-to-eat food(s) Vegetable(s)","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."},{"inspectionid":"42383","inspectionDate":"5/31/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Dishonestly presented","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"inspectionid":"42383","inspectionDate":"5/31/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \r\n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\r\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\r\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Ready to eat, potentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Beyond consume by date","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-05-31T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard."},{"inspectionid":"42383","inspectionDate":"5/31/2018","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"2-102.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall demonstrate this knowledge by compliance with this Code, by being a certified FOOD protection manager who has shown proficiency of required information through passing a test that is part of an ACCREDITED PROGRAM, or by responding correctly to the inspector's questions as they relate to the specific FOOD operation. (Pf)","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"HOT HOLDING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"40074","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","inspectionDate":"2017-09-20T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"130","pcount":"1","pfcount":"1","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"2","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"2","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"inspectionid":"40074","inspectionDate":"9/20/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"HOT HOLDING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"inspectionid":"40074","inspectionDate":"9/20/2017","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","criticalViolationType":"Yes","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-09-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"38068","establishmentid":"5403","name":"Detroit Shawarma/Spice Giant","inspectionDate":"2017-02-21T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inspectorid":"130","pcount":"0","pfcount":"0","ccount":"0","criticalcount":"0","noncritical":"0","correctedcritical":"0","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"5403"}}